(647) 865-3991 Oshawa, Ontario hello@devyratnasari.com

Devy Ratnasari

linkedin.com/in/devy-ratnasari github.com/devyratnasari er devyratnasari.com

Data Scientist / Data Analyst / Software Developer

Skilled and results-oriented professional with two years experience in software development with a focus on designing and building an end-user application. Successfully improve the efficiency of the business process. Independently managed, designed and implemented business processes for the company. Awarded recognition for excellent company performance. Viewed as a strong problem solver in intense and demanding environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Python, C#, Java, .net, FlaskAPI, SQL, Mysql, SQLAlchemy

Artificial Intelligence Machine Learning, Deep Learning, OpenCV, LLMs, TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn

Visualisation Tools Tableau, PowerBI

Cloud AWS EC2, Azure (Fundamentals), Heroku, Render

PROJECTS

Credit Card Detection (Capstone Project)

January 2022 — April 2022

- Mapped and transformed data to a consistent uniform format.
- Validate data to ensure that data is accurate, reliable, and meets the required standards.
- Built a credit card fraud detection model using multiple Machine Learning and Deep Learning algorithms.
- IEEE presentation: Youtube presentation link | Analysis: https://devyratnasari.com/capstone1.html

HM Fashion Recommendation System (Kaggle Competition)

April 2022 — May 2022

- Develop and maintained ETL processes to ensure that data is extracted from various sources, transformed into a usable format, and loaded into the appropriate system.
- · Analyzed data to identify trends and insights and created reports that can be used to inform decision-making.
- Created a recommendation system model for HM Kaggle competition using the ALS Implicit algorithm.

Automatic Attendance Using Face Recognition and Object Detection (Capstone Project)

May 2022 — August 2022

• Constructed a web application for collecting students' attendance using facial recognition. This application could simplify the lecturer's task in taking attendance and calling out each student's name and as well as reduce the possibility of other people taking attendance on behalf of someone else.

Government Bonds Order Prediction

October 2022 — November 2022

- Understanding business requirements and designing ETL processes to transform data from source systems to target systems.
- Ensured data quality and integrity by performing data validation and cleansing activities.
- Analysed Customer behaviour and developed a prediction model using Machine Learning to predict the likeliness of the user ordering bonds.
- Analysis: https://devyratnasari.com/bonds.html

EDUCATION

Artificial Intelligence Analysis, Design & Implementation - Graduate Certificate

January 2022 — August 2022

Durham College

Ontario, Canada

• Conduct research, data analysis, model development, and solution deployment in an ethical manner that protects privacy, and confidentiality, addresses data bias and transparency and ensures data integrity.

Computer Science - Bachelor Degree

September 2009 — February 2013

BINUS University

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Recognizes the new technology trends as the enablers of modern-day business analytics and intelligence for decision support
- Analyze how organizations employed business analytics and intelligence to make decisions or gain a competitive edge
- Identify Decision Support Opportunities that are supported by business analytics and intelligence.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

IT Programmer

August 2014 — July 2016

Agung Sedayu Group

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Developed a software and report system for the legal department that changes the business process from manual to digital systematised and more organised. This results in efficiency for staff and increases the ability to concentrate on important tasks.
- Trained users on how the system works.
- Assisted users with system-related problems.

(647) 865-3991 Oshawa, Ontario hello@devyratnasari.com

Devy Ratnasari

linkedin.com/in/devy-ratnasari github.com/devyratnasari per devyratnasari.com

Data Scientist / Data Analyst / Software Developer

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Restaurant Manager

June 2020 — November 2021

Sydney, Australia

Kuon Omakase & Tempura Kuon

- Leverage the usage of social media during pandemic for restaurant marketing, resulting in 100% occupancy which led to maximizing the restaurant's sales.
- Designed a customer's dictionary system that help the chefs to know and understand the customer's behaviour. Leading to better experience for the customer which increased the restaurant's sales.
- Trained 6 staff and managed the restaurants that earned an award from the Australian Good Food Guide for excellent food and service.

Human Resources Assistant March 2013 — March 2014

Alila Hotels Jakarta

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Handled medical and other staff benefits.
- Conducted training for a new staff and explain their benefits.
- Administered general affair and liaising between employee union and management if necessary.